Finding Aid for German Auxiliaries Muster Rolls
William L. Clements Library, University of Michigan
German Auxiliaries muster rolls 1776-1786 1781-1783
German Auxiliaries muster rolls
Great Britain. Army
0.25 linear feet
wclmss000814
This collection is comprised of seventy muster rolls and 15 additional letters and documents of the German regiments employed by the British to fight in the American Revolutionary War.
William L. Clements Library, University of Michigan
The collection has been microfilmed
1929, 1956. M-54, M-1042.
The collection is open for research.
History
In 1776, the British formed a treaty with the duke of Brunswick and other minor German princes that allowed the hiring of German mercenaries to bolster the British Army in North America. These German Auxiliaries muster rolls document the German regiments employed by the British to fight in the American Revolutionary War. England would pay the German princes annual subsidies, as well as additional fees, for wounded and killed soldiers. All together, approximately 30,000 men came to America from Germany and fought for the British in virtually every major campaign in the war.
This collection is organized alphabetically by the home residence of each army and then by the name of the regiment.
This collection is comprised of seventy muster rolls and 15 related letters and documents of the German regiments employed by the British to fight in the American Revolutionary War. Most of the rolls are from 1781 and 1783 and include lists for soldiers captured at Yorktown. The rolls contain details such as the rank and names of the Hessians, casualties, and remarks, such as "sick in the Barracks." These rolls are certified by British commanding officers.
The rosters list the following regiments:
Anhalt Zerbst army under Riedesel, Regiment Prinz Friedrich, Grenadier Battalion von Mengen, Regiment von Riedesel, Regiment von Specht.
Hesse-Cassel. Grenadier Battalion vacant Graff; Grenadier Battalion von Loewenstein,Company von Biesenrodt, Company von Mondorff, Company von Wachs; Grenadier Regiment d'Angelelli, Leib Conmpany; Regiment von Bunau, Leib Company; Regiment Erb Prinz (4 folls for this list names of Hessians captured at Yorktown), Company von Cochenhausen, Company von Fuchs; Regiment von Lossberg, Jr., Company von Baurmeister, Company von Biesenrodt, Company von Romrod, Company von Wilmowsky, Leib Company.
Hesse-Hanau. Artillery detachment under Pausch.
Waldeck. Third Regiment, Company von Alberti, Company von Horn, Company von Penzel.
In addition to muster rolls is a copy of the treaty executed in 1776 between the Duke of Brunswick and George III for hiring German mercenaries. Also enclosed is a barrack account for the first regiment of Anspach troops during the winter of 1777-1778; several receipts, including three accounts submitted to the Great Britain Army Victualing Office (1786); an account of payments to foreign troops in America; and a statement from a surgeon named Pralle of the Bath infantry, certifying that several men belonged to Major General de Rhetz' regiment (1781). Documents are in English and German.
Subjects:
Anhalt (Germany)--History, Military.; Braunschweig (Duchy) Heer. Prinz Friedrich Regiment--History--18th century.; Great Britain. Army--Colonial forces.; Great Britain. Army--History--Sources.; Great Britain. Army--Mercenaries.; Great Britain. Army--Registers.; Hanau-Munzenberg (Germany)--History, Military--18th century.; Hesse-Kassel (Electorate)--History, Military--18th century.; Hessian mercenaries--Registers.; Mercenary troops--Great Britain.; Pausch, Captain.; Riedesel, Friedrich Adolf, Freiherr von, 1738-1800.; Specht, Johann Friedrich, d. 1787.; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783--British forces.; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783--Participation, German.; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1781--Prisoners and prisons--Registers.; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1781--Registers.; Waldeck (Fürstentum) Waldeckische Regiment, 3te.; Yorktown (Va.)--History--Siege, 1781--Surrenders--British.
Genre Terms:
Muster rolls.
- German Auxiliaries Muster Rolls, 1776-1786 (bulk 1781-1783)
  - [Anhalt-Zerbst]. Erasmi Garitz and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 20, 1781, 1a. Muster roll of... Anhalt Zerbst Recrcuits sent over from Jevern in the year 1780... Fort Brooklyn on Long Island... Signed by Erasmi Garitz and commissary W. Porter. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Anhalt-Zerbst]. Erasmi Garitz and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 20, 1781, 1b. Erasmus Garitz to W. Porter, commissary. Muster Roll of... Anhalt Zerbst Recruits sent over from Jevern in... 1780 as muster'd... at Fort Brooklyn on Long Island, July 20, 1781. Signed by Erasmi Garitz and commissary W. Porter.
  - [Brunswick]. [Friedrich Adolf, Freiherr von] Riedesel and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 20, 1781, 2a. Muster roll of the General Staff of the Brunswick Ausiliar[y] Troops in His Britannick Majesty's Service in North America, as mustered by... Wm. Porter at Brooklyn... Signed by Riedesel and commissary W. Porter. (Folder 2)
  - [Brunswick]. Carl. de Geusau and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 20, 1781, 2b. Muster roll of the present Officers and Men of a Detachment of light infantry regiment Brunswick troops including the Recruits sent over... in... 1780. Signed by Carl de Geusau and commissary W. Porter.
  - [Brunswick]. Fr[iedrich] Cleve DS, June 26, 1783, 2c. Located in Oversize Manuscripts (see below) (Folder 3)
  - [Brunswick]. Ernst August de Bartling and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 20, 1781, 3a. Muster roll of the present Officers and Men…Fort Brooklyn on Long Island... Signed by Ernst August Bartling and commissary W. Porter.
  - [Brunswick]. Carl de Schlagenteuffel DS, June 20, 1781, 3b. List of the Names of the Recruits now in Canada, belonging to the Regiment of Brunswick Dragoons... for compleating of the different Squadrons of that Regiment. Signed by C. von Schlagenteuffel. (Folder 4)
  - [Brunswick]. [Johann Lud.] de Unger and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 20, 1781, 4a. Muster roll of the present Non Commissioned Officer and Men of a Detachment of the Regiment Prince Fredéric Brunswicks Troops including the Recruits sent over... in... 1780. Signed by de Unger and commissary W. Porter.
  - [Brunswick]. [Charles] B[aron] de Wolzogen and W[illiam] Porter DS, June 24, 1782, 4b. Rolle de la Montre du Detachement du Regiment de Prince Frederic des Trouppes de... le Duc regnant de Bronsvic... avec les changements... 25 Dec. 1781-24 June 1782. Signed by Capt. C. von Wolzogen and commissary W. Porter. (Folder 5)
  - [Brunswick]. [Balthasar] Bogislaus de Lucke and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 20, 1781, 4c. Muster roll Of the present Officers and Men of a Detachment of Major General de Rhetz Regiment Brunswicks Troops, including the Recruits sent over... in... 1780. Signed by commissary W. Porter and Major de Lucke.
  - [Brunswick]. [Julius] de Poellnitz and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 20, 1781, 5. Muster roll of the present Officers and Men of Majr: General de Riedesels Infantery Regiment of the Brunswick Troops... Signed by de Poellnitz and commissary W. Porter. (Folder 6)
  - [Brunswick]. [Regiment von Friedrich Riedesel] Document, [between 1781 and 1783], 6. State of pay of the regiment von Riedesel.
  - [Brunswick]. [Regiment von Johann Friedrich von Specht] Document, May 13, 1776, 7a. Mondirungs Anschlag auf des Obristen Specht Regiment excl. der Augmentation Anno 1776. (Folder 7)
  - [Brunswick]. A. Lützow and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 20,1781, 7b. Muster roll of the present Officers and Men of the Detachment of the Regiment Specht Brunswick troops including the Recruits sent over... in... 1780. Signed by commisary W. Porter and Capt. Lützow.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. Friedrich Platte, Johann Jacob Fritsch, Johann Henrich Brauns, Christn. Kleÿensteüber, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 4, 1782, 8a. Bataillon des Grenadiers Vacant Graff de la Compagnie du Major Hessenmüller pour 182 Jours; du 25e. Decembre 1781: jusqu'au 24e. Juin 1782 inclusivement... Muster roll. Signed by Maj. Friedrich Platte, Capt. Johann Jacob Fritsch, Lt. Johann Henrich Brauns, Lt. Christn. Kleÿensteüber, and commissary William Porter. (Folder 8)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. Friedrich Platte, G[eorge] Hohenstein, G[eorge] Schenck, B[arthold] H[enri] Schimmelpfeng, J[ean] G[eorge] Wagner, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 4, 1782, 8b. Bataillon des Grenadiers Vacant Graff de la Compagnie du Capitaine Hohenstein Pour 182. Jours du 25me. Decembre 1781: jusqu'au 24me. Juin 1782 inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Maj. Friedrich Platte; Capt. G. Hohenstein; Lt. G. Schenck, 2nd Lieut. B. H. Hohenstein, Ensign J. G. Wagner, and commissary William Porter.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. Frederich Platte, Gregorius Saltzmann, Wilhelm Studenroth, Joseph Henrich Wiederhold, and W[illia]m Porter DS, July 4, 1782, 8c. Bataillon des Grenadiers Vacant Graff de la Compagnie du Capitaine Salzmann pour 182. Jours du 25me. Decembre 1781: jusqu'au 24me. Juin 1782 inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Maj. Friedrich Platte, Capt. Gregorius Saltzmann, Lieut. Wilhelm Studenroth, 2nd Lieut. Joseph Henrich Wiederhold, and commissary William Porter. (Folder 9)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. Friedrich Platte, A[ndrea]s Oehlhans, R[einhard] Junek, J[ohannes] Koeber, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 4, 1782, 8d. Bataillon des Grenadiers Vacant Graff. Compagnie du Capitaine Sandrock pour 182 Jours du 25e. Decembre 1781. Jusqu'au 24e. Juin 1782 inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Maj. Friedrich Platte, Lieut. Andreas Oehlhans, 2nd Lieut. Reinhard Junek, 2nd Lieut. Johannes Koeber, and commissary William Porter.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. W[illia]m Loewenstein, [Hans Henrich George Wilhelm] de Biesenrodt, H[enrich] F. Zinik, W[ilhelm] L[udwig] de Romrod, Louis Friedric de Rieger, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 4, 1782, 9a. Battaillon des Grenadiers du Colonel de Loewenstein, Compagnie du Capitaine de Biesenrodt, pour 182 jours du 25me. Decembre 1781. jusqu'au 24me. Juin 1782. inlusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Col. William Loewenstein, Capt. Hans Henrich George Wilhelm de Biesenrodt, Liut. Henrich F. Zinik, 2nd Lieut. Ludwig Wilhelm de Romrod, 2nd Lieut. Louis Friedric de Rieger, and commissary William Porter. (Folder 10)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. W[illia]m Loewenstein, [Friedrich] Klingender, C[harle] Marquard, P[ier] C[hristiene] Firnhaber, H[enrich] E[rnst] Loreÿ, and commissary W[illia]m Porter DS, July 4, 1782, 9b. Bataillon des Grenadiers du Colonel de Loewenstein Compagnie du Capitaine Klingender. Pour 182. Jours de 25me. Decembr 1781 jusqu'au 24me. Juin 1782. inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Col. William Loewenstein, Capt. Friedrich Klingender, Lieut. Charle Marquard, 2nd Lieut. Pier Christiene Firnhaber, 2nd Lieut. Henrich Ernst Loreÿ, and commissary William Porter.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. W[illia]m Loewenstein, [Rudolf] Mondorff, [Otto Philip] de Münchhausen, [Christian] de Hobe, [Henrich] Hille, and W[illia]m Porter DS, July 4, 1782, 10. Battaillon des Grenadiers du Colonel de Loewenstein de la Compagnie du Capit. Mondorff. pour 182 jours, du 25me. Dec: 1781 jusqu'au 24me. Juin 1782./ inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Col. William Loewenstein, Capt. Rudolf Mondorff, Lieut. Otto Philip de Münchhausen, 2nd Lieut. Christian de Hobe, 2nd Lieut. Henrich Hille, and commissary William Porter. (Folder 11)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. W[illia]m Loewenstein, H[enrich] F[riedrich] Wachs, [Andre Louis] de Coudres, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 4, 1782, 11. Battaillon des Grenadiers du Colonel de Loewenstein du Capitaine Wachs pour 182 jours du 25me. Decembr. 1781. jusqu'au le 24me. Juin 1782 inclusivement... Signed by Col. William Loewenstein, Capt. Henrich Friedrich Wachs, 2nd Lieut. Andre Louis de Coudres, and commissary William Porter.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. J. G. Endemann, J[ean] Christoph Mulhause, F. W. Bode, Jaques Klimenhagen, and George Henri Loderhose DS, [June-July 1782], 12a. Regiment Hessois des Grenadiers du Lieutenant General Marquis D'Angelelli de la Compagne du Corps pour 182 jours du 25me. Decembre 1781. jusqu'au 24me. Juin 1782 inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Lieut. Col. J. G. Endemann, Capt. Lieut. Jean Christoph Mulhause, Major F. W. Bode, ensign Jaques Klimenhagen, and ensign George Henri Loderhose. (Folder 12)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. J. G. Endemann, Jean Adam Bauer, F. W. Bode, Frederic August Göbell, and ensign C[ÿriaeus] L[ouis] Schultz DS, June 24, 1782, 12b. Regiment Hessois des Grenadiers du Lieutenant General Marquis D'Angelelli, de la Compagnie du Capitaine Bauer, pour 182 jours du 25me. Decemr. 1781. jusqu'au 24me. Juin 1782. inclusivement..... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Lieut. Col. J. G. Endemann, Capt. Jean Adam Bauer, Maj. F. W. Bode, 2nd Lieut. Frederic August Göbell, and ensign Cÿriaeus Louis Schultz.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. J. G. Endemann, Henrÿ Christofle Fenner, F. W. Bode, Guillaume Boecking, and Jean Pierre Gerlach DS, June 24, 1782, 12c. Regiment Hessois des Grenadiers du Lieutenant General Marquis D'Angelelli, de la Compagnie du Lieutenant Colonel Endemann, pour 182 jours du 25me. Decembre 1781. jusqu'au le 24me. Juin 1782. inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Lieut. Col. J. G. Endemann, Capt. Lieut. Henrÿ Christofle Fenner, Maj. F. W. Bode, 2nd Lieut. Guillaume Boecking, and ensign Jean Pierre Gerlach. (Folder 13)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. J. G. Endemann, Philippe Henri Wiedekindl, F. W. Bode, and Philippe Pauli DS, June 24, 1782, 12d. Regiment Hessois des Grenadiers du Lieutenant General Marquis D'Angelelli, de la Compagnie du Colonel Hatzfeld pour 182 jours du 25me. Decembre 1781. jusqu-au le 24me. Juin 1782. inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Lieut. Col. J. G. Endemann, Capt. Lieut. Philippe Henri Wiedekindl, Maj. F. W. Bode, and 2nd Lieut. Philippe Pauli.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. J. R[einhold] Heilmann, P[hilip] Hillebrand, M[elchior] Martini, and Johannes Krupp DS, June 24, 1782, 12e. Regiment d'Infanterie du Colonel de Benning, de la Compagnie du Corps, pour 182 jours, du 25me. Decembre 1781 jusq-au 24me. Juin 1782. inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Capt. Lieut. Joh: Reinhold Heilmann, Lieut. Col. Philip Hillebrand, Come Maj. Melchior Martini, and Lieut. Johannes Krupp. (Folder 14)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. P[hilip] Hillebrand, M[elchior] Martini, and [Johannes] Hoerker DS, June 24, 1782, 12f. Regiment d'Infanterie du Colonel de Benning, de la Compagnie du Lieutenant Colonel Hillebrand, pour 182 jours, du 25me. Decembre 1781, jusq au 24me. Juin 1782. inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Lieut. Col. Philip Hillebrand, Come Maj. Melchior Martini, and Capt. Lieut. Johannes Hoerker.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. P[hilip] Hillenbrand, M[elchior] Martini, C[laudÿ] Stüer, and O[tto] R[oland] Scheuek DS, June 24, 1782, 12g. Regiment d'Infanterie du Colonel de Benning de la Compagnie ou Lieutenant Colonel Martini, pour 182 jours du 25me. Decembre 1781 jusq'au 24me. Juin 1782 inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Lieut. Col. Philip Hillebrand, Come Maj. Melchior Martini, Capt. Lieut. Claudÿ Stüer, and 2nd Lieut. Otto Roland Scheuek. (Folder 15)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. P[hilip] Hillebrand, M[elchior] Martini, D[ietrich] Reinhard, F[rantz] A[dam] Kuhl, and B. E. Eckhard DS, June 24, 1782, 12h. Regiment d'Infantrie du Colonel de Benning de la Compagnie du Major de Prueschenck pour 182 jours du 25me. Decembre 1781 jusq'au 24me Juin 1782. inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Lieut. Col. Philip Hillebrand, Come Maj. Melchior Martini, Capt. Lieut. Dietrich Reinhard, Lieut. Frantz Adam Kuhl, and 2nd Lieut. B. E. Eckhard.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. P[hilip] Hillebrand, M[elchior] Martini, J[eremias] Roepenak, J. Martini, and F[riedrich] Kroeschell DS, June 24, 1782, 12i. Regiment d'Infanterie du Colonel de Benning, de la Compagnie du Capitaine Sonneborn pour 182 jours du 25me. Decembre 1781, jusq'au 24me. Juin 1782. inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Lieut. Col. Philip Hillebrand, Come Maj. Melchior Martini, Lieut. Jeremias Roepenak, 2nd Lieut. J. Martini [Martinus Martini?], and ensign Friedrich Kroeschell. (Folder 16)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. R[udolph] von Bünau, [Wilhelm] H[enrich] Bauer, H. Hessenmüller, F. G[ottlieb] Greben, F. D. Selig, and commissary W[illiam] Porter DS, July 3, 1782, 13a. Regiment d'Infanterie du Colonell de Bünau, de la Compagnie du Corps 182 Jours du 25me. Decembre 1781 Jusq'ue au 24me. Juin 1782, inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Colonel Come Capitain Rudolph von Bünau, 2nd Lieut. Wilhelm Henrich Bauer, Maj. H. Hessenmüller, ensign F. Gottlieb Greben, ensign F. D. Selig, and commissary William Porter.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. R[udolph] von Bünau, H. Hessenmüller, P[hil.] F[erdinand] Wolff de Gudenberg, P[eter] Munch, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 3, 1782, 13b. Regiment d'Infanterie du Collonel de Bünau, de la Compagnie Vacant Major Boecking, pour 182 jours du 25me. Decembr 1781 jusqu'au 24me. Juin 1782. inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Chef et Commandeur Rudolph von Bünau, Maj. H. Hessenmüller, 2nd Lieut. Phil. Ferdinand Wolff de Gudenberg, ensign Peter Munch, and commissary William Porter. (Folder 17)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. R[udolph] von Bünau, [Joh. Christian] Goebell, H. Hessenmüller, [George] Lyncker, [Joh. Peter] Quentell, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 3, 1782, 13c. Regiment d'Infanterie du Colonel de Bünau de la Compagnie du Capitain Goebell pour 182 Jours du 25me. Decembre 1781 Jusq'au 24me. Juin 1782 inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Chef et Commandeur Rudolph von Bünau, Capt. Joh. Christian Goebell, Maj. H. Hessenmüller, 2nd Lieut. George Lyncker, ensign Joh. Peter Quentell, and commissary William Porter.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. R[udolph] von Bünau, Philipp Christian Firnhaber, H. Hessenmüller, C[hristian] O[tto] Frohn, Carl Hillebrand, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 3, 1782, 13d. Regiment Infanterie du Colonel de Bünau, de la Compagnie du Major Platte, pour 182. Jours, du 25me. Decembre 1781 jusq'au 24me. Juin 1782 inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Chef et Commandeur Rudolph von Bünau, Capt. Lieut. Philipp Christian Firnhaber, Maj. H. Hessenmüller, 2nd Lieut. Christian Otto Frohn, 2nd Lieut. Carl Hillebrand, and commissary William Porter (Folder 18)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. R[udolph] von Bünau, Joh. Adam Scheffer, H. Hessenmüller, Christoph Feldner, R[einhard] F[ried.] Scheffer, F[ried.] W[ilhelm Küster], and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 3, 1782, 13e. Regiment d'Infanterie du Colonel de Bünau de la Compagnie du Colonel Scheffer pour 182 jours du 25me. Decembr 1781. jusq au 24me. Juin 1782 inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Chef et Commandeur Rudolph von Bünau, Col. Joh. Adam Scheffer, Maj. H. Hessenmüller, Capt. Lieut. Christoph Feldner, 2nd Lieut. Reinhard Fried. Scheffer, ensign Fried. Wilhelm Küster, and commissary William Porter.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. C[arl] P[hilipp] Heÿmell, Carl de Wurmb, P[hiliph] H. Murhard, Henri de Bardeleben, W[ilhelm] Freÿenhagen, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 5, 1782, 13f. Located in Oversize Manuscripts (see below)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. C[arl] P[hilipp] Heÿmell, Carl de Wurmb, J. F[riedrich] Venator, C[arl] E. Henckell, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 5, 1782, 13g. Located in Oversize Manuscripts (see below)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. C[arl] P[hilipp] Heÿmell, Carl de Wurmb, Carl de Haussen, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 5, 1782, 13h. Located in Oversize Manuscripts (see below)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. C[arl] P[hilipp] Heÿmell, Carl de Wurmb, F[ried.] [Wilh.] Geister, [Carl Fried.] de Nagell, F[ried. F.] Murhard, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 5, 1782, 13i. Located in Oversize Manuscripts (see below)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. C[arl] P[hilipp] Heÿmell, Carl de Wurmb, E[rasmus] E[rnst] Hinte, K[ristoph Dietrich] von Donop, E[manuel] R[osenus] Hausmann, G. Lehrbach, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 5, 1782, 13j. Regiment d'Infanterie de Donop de la Compagnie du Colonel Hinte pour 182 jours du 25me. Decembre 1781 jusqu'au 24me. Juin 1782 inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Col. Carl Philipp Heÿmell, Maj. Carl de Wurmb, Col. Erasmus Ernst Hinte, Maj. Carl de Wurmb, Capt. Kristoph Dietrich von Donop, Lieut. Emanuel Rosenus Hausmann, ensign G. Lehrbach, and commissary William Porter. (Folder 21)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. J. Fr[ederic] de Cochenhausen, [Michael] Waldenberg, Reinh. Ungewitter, Louis DesCoudres, and W[illiam] Porter DS, [June-July 1782], 14. Regiment Infanterie du Prince Hereditaire de Hesse de la Compagnie du Colonel de Cochenhausen pour 182 jours du 25me. Decembr. 1781. jusqu'au 24me. Juin 1782. inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Col. J. Frederic de Cochenhausen, Maj. Waldenberg, 2nd Lieut. Reinh. Ungewitter, ensign Louis DesCoudres, and commissary William Porter.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. J. Fr[ederic] de Cochenhausen, [Mathew] de Fuchs, [Michael] Waldenberg, [Guillaume] v[on] Andersohn, [Valentin] Schoenewolff, J[ean] H[ermann] Gebhard, and W[illiam] Porter DS, [June-July 1782], 15a. Regiment Infanterie du Prince Hereditaire de Hesse de la Compagnie du Lieut: Colonel de Fuchs Pour 182 Jours du 25me. Decembr. 1781 Jusqu au 24me. Juin 1782. Inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Col. J. Frederic de Cochenhausen, Lieut. Col. Mathieu de Fuchs, Maj. Waldenberg, 2nd Lieut. Guillaume von Andersohn, ensign Valentin Schoenewolff, Capt. Lieut. Jean Hermann Gebhard, and commissary William Porter. (Folder 22)
  - [Hesse Cassel]. J. Fr[erderic] de Cochenhausen, C[aspar] Kümmell, [Michael] Waldenberg, J. D[iet.] Pfaff, and W[illiam] Porter DS, [June-July 1782], 15b. Regiment Infanterie du Prince Hereditaire de Hesse de la Compagnie du General Major de Hachenberg pour 182 Jours du 25me. Decembr 1781 jusqu'au 24me. Juin 1782 inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Col. J. Frerderic de Cochenhausen, Capt. Caspar Kümmell, Maj. Waldenberg, 2nd Lieut. J. Diet. Pfaff, and commissary William Porter.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. J. Fr[ederic] de Cochenhausen, [Michael] Waldenberg, F[rederic] de Kendell, F[rederic] Wyneken, and W[illiam] Porter DS, [June-July 1782], 15c. Regiment Infanterie du Prince Hereditaire de la Compagnie du Major Waldenberg, pour 182 jours de 25me. Dec. 1781 jusqu au 24me. uin 1782 inclusivement... Muster roll, Dec. 25, 1781-June 24, 1782. Signed by Col. J. Frederic de Cochenhausen, Maj. Michael Waldenberg, 2nd Lieut. Frederic de Kendell, ensign Frederic Wyneken, and commissary William Porter. (Folder 23)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. G[eorge] E. Lengecke DS, March 12, 1778, 15d. Return of Emendements made in the Quarters of Colonel de Lengeckes Batallion of Hessian Grenadiers. Signed by George E. von Lengecke.
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. C[hristian] V[on] Romrod, E[manuel] de Wilmowsky, J[ohann] L[udolph] Rodemann, E[hrhard] de Drach, C[arl] de Ehrenstein, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 5, 1782, 16. Located in Oversize Manuscripts (see below)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. C[hristian] V[on] Romrod, H[ans] M[oritz] de Biesenrodt, E[manuel] de Wilmowsky, [Carl Henrich] de Toll, M[artin] L[udwig] Wiscker, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 5, 1782, 17. Located in Oversize Manuscripts (see below)
  - [Hesse-Cassel]. C[hristian] V[on] Romrod, E[manuel] de Wilmowsky, J[ohann] M[elchior] Rothe, C[arl Wilhelm] de Bultzingsloewen, C[arl] de Bode, and W[illiam] Porter DS, July 5, 1782, 18. Located in Oversize Manuscripts (see below)